Okay, so what if you want to have code
that relies on other code that you might
not get? Um, and so you need to do two
asynchronous operations, meaning you
need to get data from one source and get
data from another source. Um, remember
last time we simulated that when we were
doing it with functional callbacks. We
simulated that by pausing for three
seconds and then pausing for five or I
don't remember the number of seconds we
paused but we paused for a certain
amount of time and then we paused for an
additional amount of time once the first
operation was complete. Let's say we
want to do that here. So one way um what
I've done is I brought in our
incrementtor. So I've hidden the code
here so it doesn't distract from what
we're doing but it's just going to print
out how many seconds have passed. And
then here I've written a function that
returns a promise. So the promise that
we wrote in the last one resolved hello
world after a set amount of time. This
will give us a promise that resolves
after a set amount of time that we pass
it. Because it's a function, the
function will return a promise. And
because it's a promise, we can do things
with that promise. So for example, I
could say let promise one equal wait.
And then how long would I like to wait?
Well, let's do the wait 3 seconds first.
And then I want once it's done, I want
to print out the results. of promise
one, I want to print out this hello
world. So after 3 seconds, I want to
print out hello world. Once that's done,
I want to print out hello world again an
additional 5 seconds later, meaning at
the 8second mark. So I'd say promise 1.n
and then it receives the value hello
world and passes it into a function. So
I'm going to write that function that
accepts value. And because it's only one
parameter, I don't need the parenthesis.
I put them in the last video just for um
consistency, but you don't need them and
so I'm not going to put them anymore. So
here I'm going to take the value and I'm
going to log it out to the console.
console.log Oh boy, not typing well
today. console.log.
And we'll log that value. And let's just
save this and make sure it works.
Um okay so if we reload printed out
hello world immediately which means
there is some problem with my code. Um
return a new promise resolve reject
um take in the number of milliseconds
resolve it after oh I apologize this
needs to be wrapped in a function um an
anonymous function. So if we save that
and we come over waited 1 2 3 seconds
and then it prints out hello world and
then wait 4 6 7 8 at this point is when
we want to call hello world again. So
let's go over here and you might think
that you could just do another promise.
So, I could say let promise 2 equal wait
5,000 milliseconds.
And then I'll say promise 2
then um and then I'll pass in 5,000
milliseconds or
or sorry
tongue twisted today. I will take the
value and I'll log the value.
Okay. So, what I've done is I've made a
promise and then once it's done, I'm
logging it. Then I made another promise
and once it's done, I'm logging it. This
is where we're going to run into a
similar issue we ran into with
callbacks. So, we go 1 2 3 Hello World 4
Hello World. We actually wanted it 5
minutes, sorry, 5 seconds after the
first hello world, not 5 seconds after
the start of our program. So, if we want
to do that, then we need to be able to
chain promises together. And that's the
amazing thing about then. As long as you
return a promise inside of your then
statement, then you can keep chaining
then together. So let's come back over
here. So on this first promise, I said
wait 3,00 seconds. Once you're done,
console.log it. And I'm actually going
to make this into a multi-line function
by putting curly braces.
Boy,
typing is not going well today. And I'm
going to console.log the value.
Then underneath what I'm going to do is
I'm going to type the word return. And
then I'm going to say wait. And how long
do I want to wait? This time I want to
wait an additional 5,000 milliseconds.
Because it's returning it, I could store
that in another promise. Or rather than
storing it in another promise, at the
end of this then, I can tag on another
then. So, just like you could take a
string and uppercase it and that
returned a string and you could store it
in a new variable, but you could also
take a string and then uppercase it and
then split it and you could just keep
chaining string methods together. As
long as your then returns a promise, you
can string those together. So, right
here, I could say then and take uh the
second value and console.log
the second value. So, if we save that
and I'm going to format my code so it
looks a little neater. So I'm saying
create a promise. Once that promise
resolves, log the result and then create
another promise and then log that
result. So if we save this and we come
over here, it's waited 1 2 3 seconds.
Hello world. 4 5 6 7 8 Hello World. And
then we were able to create um code that
ran after a set delay based on another
set delay. And we're able to do that
using promises.